const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="commerce",t=200,o=120,a=[{id:452,question:"The most reliable and efficient means of conveying urgent documents is through",option:{a:"postal order ",b:"ordinary letters ",c:"registered letters ",d:"courier services"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:804,question:"The machine used for sending telex messages is known as a",option:{a:"radar",b:"fax machine",c:"Dictaphone",d:"teleprinter."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:399,question:"The major problem encountered in international trade is that of  ",option:{a:"distance ",b:"differences in culture ",c:"politics ",d:"differences in currency "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:61,question:"Commercialization of government corporations brings about an increase in the level of",option:{a:"money supply in the economy",b:"distrust among business operators",c:"competition among business operators",d:"social responsibility"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:40,question:"Fluctuations in the supply of goods may be eliminated if the distribution system maintains",option:{a:"modern technology ",b:"a team of retailers",c:"warehouse services  ",d:"sufficient middlemen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:703,question:"Bank overdraft as a short term source of fund is",option:{a:"an overdrawn account",b:"granted to a newly opened account",c:"repayable after more than a year",d:"a current liability."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:236,question:"An example of a non-insurable risk is ",option:{a:"burglary ",b:"speculation ",c:"fire ",d:"accident "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:149,question:"Consumers require protection against exploitation to ensure ",option:{a:"adequate consumer awareness",b:"availability of product variety",c:"the sale of quality products",d:"increased aggregate demand."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:594,question:"In the marketing mix, place refers to",option:{a:"channel of distribution",b:"location of the factory",c:"the market place",d:"where the product is located"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:198,question:"An activity that involves derivation of raw materials from land and sea is ",option:{a:"construction ",b:"farming ",c:"agriculture ",d:"extraction "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:696,question:"Production involves",option:{a:"making goods available where and when needed",b:"changing the form of goods, moving and making them available as needed",c:"the manufacturing of goods and provision of services",d:"the assembling of all necessary parts to produce a finished product."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:224,question:"The pooling of business information for the benefit of members is a major function of a ",option:{a:"pressure group ",b:"trade association ",c:"cultural group ",d:"trade union "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:72,question:"A partnership is dissolved when",option:{a:"the business suffers a loss",b:"there is bankruptcy",c:"there is consistent theft",d:"there is a misunderstanding between partners"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:190,question:"The difference between the buying and selling price of shares is known as   ",option:{a:"brokerage",b:"margin   ",c:"jobber's turn   ",d:"gross profit."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:283,question:"The function which ensures that set objectives are attained by an organization is ",option:{a:"planning ",b:"directing ",c:"staffing ",d:"controlling "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:672,question:"A supplier of flour who intends to sign a contract with a baker 	through post can establish a binding agreement only",option:{a:"after the offeror has made an offer.",b:"when the offeror’s letter has reached the offeree.",c:"when the. Offeree’s letter has been posted.",d:"after the offeree’s letter has been received by the offeror."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:587,question:"Which of the following towns was NOT an initial commercial centre in Nigeria?",option:{a:"Kano",b:"Lagos",c:"Maiduguri",d:"Yola"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:731,question:"An aspect of the law which allows an exclusive right for a limited number of years is a",option:{a:"copyright",b:"trade mark",c:"ratification",d:"patent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:666,question:"A document that serves as an instrument for preferential tariff is referred to as",option:{a:"an indent",b:"a certificate of origin",c:"a consular invoice",d:"an advice note."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:211,question:"Maimani Plc, whose nominal capital is made up of 500 000 ordinary shares of 50k each, decided to offer 80% of it to the public and realized only 50% of the amount due. Determine the company’s reserve share capital ",option:{a:"N2500 000",b:"N1000 000",c:"N1500 000",d:"N2000 000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:455,question:"The difference between indemnity insurance and non-indemnity insurance is that the latter provides ",option:{a:"cover for exporters against risks ",b:"cover for importers against risks ",c:"full payment to the insured ",d:"consolation payment to the insured "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:783,question:"One of the major functions of a chamber of commerce is to",option:{a:"promote and protect trade, industry and agriculture",b:"advise members on regulations of other countries",c:"settle disputes that arise out of trade",d:"publish books and periodicals desired by members."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:841,question:"An obstacle to international trade is",option:{a:"trade imbalance between   countries",b:"availability of  local market",c:"quantity and quality of labour",d:"cost of finance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:439,question:"The provision of quality and safe products which guarantee the health of consumers is an example of ",option:{a:"quality control ",b:"price control ",c:"civic responsibility ",d:"social responsibility "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:78,question:"An engineer in government employ is to be rendering   ",option:{a:"primary service   ",b:"tertiary service ",c:"indirect service   ",d:"direct service. "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:269,question:"One major advantage of transportation to a business is to",option:{a:"extend the firm’s market coverage",b:"ensure that goods are produced faster",c:"procure raw materials cheaply ",d:"ensure the quality of products"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:142,question:"The Customs and Excise Department is responsible for the collection of",option:{a:"royalties ",b:"tariffs",c:"taxes ",d:"charges."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:654,question:"The  lumbering of trees by a furniture company is an example of",option:{a:"primary production",b:"secondary production",c:"tertiary production",d:"Indirect production"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:311,question:"Selling goods in foreign countries at prices below their marginal cost is ",option:{a:"dumping ",b:"depreciation ",c:"devaluation ",d:"discounting "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:263,question:"One of he facilities enjoyed by a current account holder is ",option:{a:"a dividend  ",b:"a bonus",c:"an overdraft ",d:"interest on deposits"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:779,question:"Who are the parties to the contract of renting the room?",option:{a:"Musa and Jacob",b:"Musa and Audu",c:"Adamu and Musa",d:"Audu and Jocob."},section:"Musa rented a room to Adamu for N= 1, 500 and N= 1,000 part-payment was made. Adamu brought Audu and Jacob his friends to stay in the room. The two friends later paid the balance of N= 500 to Musa.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:829,question:"One of the most important function of marketing is",option:{a:"encouraging research activities to meet needs",b:"creating classes of merchants among businessmen",c:"the extension of markets for businesses",d:"providing finances to businesses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:316,question:"An agent who brings a customer into business contact with his principal is known as ",option:{a:"a del credere agent ",b:"an auctioneer",c:"a factor",d:"a broker"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:608,question:"Which of the following is not a factor of production?",option:{a:"Capital",b:"land",c:"Labour",d:"Staffing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:130,question:"A   feature   common   to   privatization   and commercialization is  ",option:{a:"profit-making    ",b:"credit sales ",c:"market expansion ",d:"price increases."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:490,question:"Which of the following is not a source of finance to a sole proprietor?",option:{a:"Trade Credit",b:"Overdrafts",c:"Debentures",d:"Leasing of equipment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:237,question:"The coordinating section of the central processing unit that manages the flow of data is the ",option:{a:"arithmetic logic unit",b:"control unit",c:"magnetic unit",d:"register"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:38,question:"Commerce includes all the occupations concerned with ",option:{a:"sales  ",b:"production",c:"marketing    ",d:"distribution "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:786,question:"In the line type of organizational structure",option:{a:"the lines of authority are vertical",b:"there is the application of division of labour",c:"specialization is carried to a maximum degree",d:"the lines of authority are horizontal."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:513,question:"When a customer writes a cheque in his own name and withdraws cash with it from his account he is both the",option:{a:"drawee and the payee",b:"drawer and the payer",c:"drawee and the drawer",d:"drawer and the payee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:121,question:"The conversion of raw materials into finished products creates ",option:{a:"form utility ",b:"marginal utility",c:"place utility ",d:"time utility."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:379,question:"Activities undertaken to create awareness for goods by conducting contests is ",option:{a:"marketing concept ",b:"consumerism ",c:"sales promotion ",d:"marketing mix"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:227,question:"The four Ps of marketing are",option:{a:"product, place, process and promotion ",b:"price, product, property and place",c:"price, product, place and promotion ",d:"price, production, place and property "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:543,question:"The final link in the chain of distribution is the",option:{a:"agent",b:"consumer",c:"manufacturer",d:"retailer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:425,question:"Dealing in quoted securities on the Nigeria Stock Exchange is restricted to authorized ",option:{a:"companies ",b:"brokers ",c:"investors ",d:"principals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:84,question:"Which of the middlemen in the channel of distribution has title to the goods he distributes?",option:{a:"The merchant wholesaler ",b:"The agent",c:"the limited wholesaler ",d:"The retailer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:453,question:"An undertaking given by a person to another assuring his integrity is ",option:{a:"proximate clause ",b:"fidelity guarantee ",c:"subrogation ",d:"insurable interest "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:111,question:"The limit of functions, activities and personnel that a supervisor can effectively manage  in a business organization  is  ",option:{a:"spun of control ",b:" delegation of authority ",c:"chain of command ",d:" authority and responsibility"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:434,question:"The body which ensures that consumers are protected against harmful product in Nigeria is ",option:{a:"NAFDAC ",b:"NDLEA",c:"SON",d:"CPC"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:850,question:"A guarantee given by one person or party to another in which 	the integrity of the person is assured is",option:{a:"fidelity",b:"term assurance",c:"subrogation",d:"indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:384,question:"The body charged with the responsibility of regulating foods and drugs in Nigeria is the ",option:{a:"SON",b:"NDLEA",c:"NAFDAC",d:"CAC"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:25,question:"What is the role of the capital market in the privatization exercise in Nigeria?    ",option:{a:"Selling the shares and stocks of the companies to be  privatized ",b:"Encouraging private companies to  participate in the exercise ",c:"Negotiating with individuals who want to buy public companies",d:"Advertising for government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:341,question:"A device that enables the downloading of information from the internet is the ",option:{a:"floppy drive ",b:"compact disk ",c:"modem ",d:"blue tooth "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:693,question:"One of the major reasons for merger is to",option:{a:"reduce the number of unskilled manpower",b:"increase the number of skilled manpower.",c:"prevent liquidation.",d:"liberalize the market."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:784,question:"Departmentalization is an aspect of",option:{a:"planning",b:"organizing",c:"directing",d:"controlling."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:278,question:"A body established to protect the interest of members against the exploitation of retail traders and manufacturers is the ",option:{a:"wholesalers association ",b:"consumer’s  association ",c:"government agency ",d:"workers’ union "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:77,question:"The Nigerian Telecommunications Limited is a",option:{a:"Jointly owned company ",b:"public corporation ",c:"privately owned company ",d:"public company. "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:471,question:"In a staff-authority relationship, the opinion of a specialist is one department to another is ",option:{a:"a directive ",b:"an advice ",c:"a command",d:"a delegation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:201,question:"The process of changing the form of a raw material is known as  ",option:{a:"fabrication ",b:"extraction ",c:"conversion ",d:"production "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:200,question:`Given: I. shoe marker    II. Policeman     III. Fisherman    IV. Gardener    V. Broker .    The persons engaged in primary occupation are 
`,option:{a:"I, III and IV ",b:"III and IV",c:"III and V",d:"I , II and V"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:598,question:"The transfer of enterprises from private to state ownership for economic or social reasons is referred to as",option:{a:"commercialization",b:"indigenization",c:"industrialization",d:"naturalization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:716,question:"A printer that burns the print image onto the photosensitive drum is called",option:{a:"dot matrix printer",b:"daisy wheel printer",c:"laser printer",d:"thermal printer."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:793,question:"Which of the following best describes the scope of commerce?",option:{a:"All forms of commercial exchanges and the manufacturing industry",b:"Buying and selling and the construction industry",c:"All occupational exchanges relating to industries and commercial activities",d:"Buying and selling as well as the extraction of natural resources."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:794,question:"Capital as a factor of production can be used as",option:{a:"money that is regarded as asset",b:"goods that are useful in business",c:"input for further production",d:"services that provide satisfaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:14,question:"One important requirement for the membership of the ECOWAS is ",option:{a:"integrity ",b:"independence ",c:"landmass   ",d:"population"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:343,question:"One way by which a business can discharge its social responsibility to its community is to ",option:{a:"hold monthly meetings of its customers",b:"build houses for its executives ",c:"award scholarship to staff children ",d:"build public health centres."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:825,question:"Recognized members of the Stock Exchange who buy and sell securities on their own behalf are known as",option:{a:"bolls",b:"jobbers",c:"brokers",d:"stags."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:719,question:"The major condition for obtaining loan in thrift, credit and loans cooperative societies is",option:{a:"provision of collateral security",b:"a high level of education",c:"possession of a large business",d:"an approved project plan."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:715,question:"The computer using linear integrated circuit technology coupled with quantification of data in terms of length and distance is known as",option:{a:"digital computer",b:"analogue computer",c:"mainframe computer",d:"hybrid computer."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:813,question:"The Stock Exchange is a market where",option:{a:"long-term securities are sold",b:"all types of securities are sold",c:"short-term securities are sold",d:"medium-term securities are sold."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:359,question:"The purchase of goods under the CWO system of payment implies that ",option:{a:"money must be enclosed when ordering ",b:"payment must be made on delivery ",c:"payment must be made on the spot.",d:"cash must be paid on the spot "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:832,question:"The principal objectives of the Central Bank of Nigeria can be classified broadly into",option:{a:"bankers’ bank, lender of last resort and issuance of currency",b:"service, currency management and financial intermediation",c:"banking services, foreign exchange operations and open",d:"markets operations service, monetary policy and developmental functions."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:699,question:"Which of these is both merit and demerit in partnership?",option:{a:"The number of partners",b:"Its unlimited nature",c:"The bearing of risk",d:"The withdrawal of a major partner."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:607,question:"If a retailer Mr. Aigbojie buys goods manufactured by Adefila Limited from wholesaler Mrs. Jumai, who will prepare the delivery note?",option:{a:"Mr. Aigbojie",b:"Adefila Limited",c:"Mr. Jumai",d:"Mr. Aigbojie and Adefila Limited"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:759,question:"The trade discount receivable by Mr. Bacus is",option:{a:"N= 4,500",b:"N= 7,500",c:"N= 10,500",d:"N= 12,000."},section:"Mr. Awala is a retailer of a single product. He sells at the standard price. He gives a trade discount of 5%,quantity discount of 3% for a volume above 1000 units and a cash discount of 2/10 net 30  the existing selling price of the product is N= 100 per unit. Mr. Bacus purchased 1500 units of the product on credit and promised to pay Mr. Awala in cash in the first 10 days after purchase.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:354,question:"Balance of payment problems arise if a country’s ",option:{a:"exports is more than imports",b:"imports is more than exports",c:"currently is devaluated",d:"Invisible exports is more than visible exports "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:433,question:"Yahaya bought a piece of furniture on a credit sale agreement from Ahmed and resold it to Ali before all installments were made. The court upheld that Ahmed could not recover possession of the items from Ali. The reason for the judement was because ",option:{a:"ownership was transferred on completion of installment ",b:"ownership was transferred on delivery ",c:"Yahaya could not pass title to a third party ",d:"Ali was still indebted to Yahaya"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:76,question:"Occupations are classified into",option:{a:"production, labour and economics",b:"extraction, construction and manufacturing",c:"industry, commerce and serves",d:"trade, aids to trade and services."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:873,question:"The ECOBANK is the initiative of",option:{a:"some well-meaning Nigerian shareholders",b:"the Federal Government of  Nigeria",c:"West African states to foster trade",d:"the Lagos State Government to enhance capital mobilization."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:735,question:"A chamber of commerce is an association made up of",option:{a:"entrepreneurs",b:"manufacturers",c:"merchants",d:"importers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:622,question:"Which of the following is the most suitable means of 	transporting bulky goods from Lagos to Kaduna? By",option:{a:"Train",b:"Airplane",c:"Ship",d:"Lorry"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:717,question:"A console is a device used in",option:{a:"moving an indicator on the screen",b:"communicating between operator and programme",c:"holding magnetic tape reel",d:"forming characters by heating sensitive ribbon."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:792,question:"The major responsibility of an entrepreneur is",option:{a:"employing all factors of production in the business",b:"coordinating and determining the proportion of what to produce",c:"planning and organizing all activities in the business",d:"directing and controlling all the affairs of the business."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:49,question:"Discounts offered by firms to middlemen for bulk purchases are ",option:{a:"A   trade discounts",b:"sales  bonanza    ",c:"cash discounts ",d:"seasonal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:788,question:"One of the obstacles  to achieving the objectives of ECOWAS is",option:{a:"lack of a common currency",b:"colonial linkages",c:"sovereignty of states",d:"language differences."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:212,question:"In order to prevent liquidity problems in commercial banks, the central bank uses.",option:{a:"moral suasion  ",b:"fiscal policy",c:"reserve ratio",d:"taxation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:71,question:"In GIF contracts, risk passes at the time of shipment but the property does not pass until",option:{a:"there is physical transfer of goods",b:"the shipping manifests are signed",c:"the shipping documents are transferred",d:"the goods on board are delivered."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:687,question:"Where a manufacturer collects money from wholesalers in exchange for goods produced is referred to as",option:{a:"charge account.",b:"trading checks.",c:"trade credit.",d:"I owe you."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:560,question:"Those engaged in extraction, manufacturing, and construction occupations are called ___ workers.",option:{a:"commercial",b:"direct",c:"indirect",d:"industrial"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:225,question:"An association to which all chambers of commerce in Nigeria are affiliated is the ",option:{a:"Nigeria Labour Congress ",b:"National Association of Chambers of Commerce, Industry, Mines and Agriculture",c:"Nigeria Association of Chambers of Commerce, Industry, Mines and Agriculture ",d:"Nigeria Stock Exchange "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:685,question:"Which of the following is NOT backed by gold but by government securities?",option:{a:"Fiduciary note.",b:"Fiat money.",c:"Token money.",d:"Commodity money."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:797,question:"Which of the following countries are members the Lake Chad Basin Commission?",option:{a:"Niger and Cameroun",b:"Benin and Niger",c:"Chad and Benin",d:"Nigeria and Mali."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:28,question:"A group of assets which a business acquires with the intention of reselling them are referred to as",option:{a:"  current assets    ",b:"investment assets",c:"fixed assets    ",d:"intangible assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:35,question:"What does v represent?",option:{a:"Aids to trade",b:"Advertising  ",c:"Manufacturing  ",d:"Industry"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:516,question:"Which of the following services is not rendered by commercial banks?",option:{a:"Business advice",b:"Currency notes issue",c:"Accepting deposits",d:"Credit transfer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:153,question:"The major achievement of ECOWAS is",option:{a:"the expansion of regional trade",b:"the emergence of a monetary union",c:"infrastructure! development in member countries",d:"mobility of labour among member countries."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:801,question:"The commercialization of public enterprises aimed at",option:{a:"increasing efficiency and making the enterprises self-sufficient",b:"advertising a promoting the goods and services of the enterprises",c:"increased assistance and patronage of the enterprises by the public",d:"selling the goods and services of the enterprises."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:191,question:"Which of the following is a risk-free security?",option:{a:"Preference share.   ",b:"Ordinary share.",c:"Treasury bill.    ",d:"Debenture."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:753,question:"The difference between total current assets and total current liabilities of a business is known as",option:{a:"quick ratio",b:"liquidity ratio",c:"working capital",d:"circulating capital."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:215,question:"A person who buys new issues with a view of reselling at a higher price in the near future is referred to as a ",option:{a:"bull ",b:"bear ",c:"dealer ",d:"stage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:781,question:"The maximum number of shareholders in a public liability company is",option:{a:"twenty",b:"fifty",c:"one hundred",d:"unlimited."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:845,question:"Goods that are manufactured or acquired by the seller after the contract of sale are",option:{a:"specialty goods",b:"future goods",c:"specific goods",d:"general goods"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:268,question:"The most important reason for the existence of insurance business is to ",option:{a:"prevent the occurrence of any loss",b:"spread losses to all covered participants",c:"provide for the replacement of facilities",d:"encourage individuals to save"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:675,question:"One of the functions of the retailer is",option:{a:"granting credit facilities to close relatives",b:"provision of after-sales services",c:"branding and packaging of goods.",d:"warehousing of goods."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:152,question:"Citizens are against privatisation mainly because of ",option:{a:"the rationalization of organizations",b:"increased prices of goods and services",c:"the likelihood of monopoly",d:"ineffective management."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:202,question:"In the long run, all factors of production are ",option:{a:"fixed ",b:"variable ",c:"marginal ",d:"constant "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:109,question:"The setting of objectives for an organization and determining how to accomplish them is ",option:{a:"social responsibility  ",b:"planning  ",c:"organizing",d:" decision-making."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:818,question:"The organizational structure that relates the positions of specialists to the line managers is called",option:{a:"line structure",b:"staff structure",c:"line and staff structure",d:"functional structure."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:398,question:"The basis for international trade is embedded in the principle of ",option:{a:"absolute advantage ",b:"globalization ",c:"deregulation",d:"comparative advantage "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:569,question:"The money paid to savings account holders by banks after a period of transaction is called",option:{a:"dividend",b:"gain",c:"interest",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:183,question:"Which of the following requires payment into the payee's account?   ",option:{a:"Crossed cheque.",b:"Traveller’s cheque.    ",c:" Open cheque.",d:"Certified cheque."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:60,question:"The computer that functions by taking discrete numbers and  performing mathematical calculations is called ",option:{a:"mainframe ",b:"digital ",c:"hybride",d:"analogue."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:694,question:"A major function of commerce is to",option:{a:"facilitate human satisfaction through exchange",b:"eliminate trade barriers",c:"provide raw materials for manufacturers",d:"influence government policies"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:606,question:"The oldest and commonest form of business in Nigeria is",option:{a:"partnership",b:"the co-operative society",c:"sole proprietorship",d:"joint stock venture"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:791,question:"Secondary production has to do with changing the",option:{a:"shape of raw materials through construction operations",b:"physical form of raw materials into finished goods",c:"utility of raw materials by an engineering process",d:"nature of raw materials through manufacturing processes."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:432,question:"A person who in consideration for an extra commission, takes responsibility for goods sold on credit and in case of default is a ",option:{a:"commission agent",b:"del credere agent ",c:"broker ",d:"factor "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:492,question:"A private company is one which",option:{a:"must publish its audited account",b:"floats its shares on the stock exchange market",c:"restricts the rights to transfer its shares",d:"is owned by a maximum of twenty members merger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:438,question:"Modern mans of payment is greatly facilitated by ",option:{a:"e-commerce ",b:"paper money ",c:"e-banking ",d:"D credit transfer "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:760,question:"If  Mr. Bacus fulfils his promise, he will be entitled to a cash discount of",option:{a:"N= 2,760",b:"N= 3,000",c:"N= 6,500",d:"N= 9,500."},section:"Mr. Awala is a retailer of a single product. He sells at the standard price. He gives a trade discount of 5%,quantity discount of 3% for a volume above 1000 units and a cash discount of 2/10 net 30  the existing selling price of the product is N= 100 per unit. Mr. Bacus purchased 1500 units of the product on credit and promised to pay Mr. Awala in cash in the first 10 days after purchase.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:238,question:"An agreement between two parties which is enforceable by law is a ",option:{a:"promise ",b:"warranty ",c:"contract ",d:"condition "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"}],n={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,i as subject,o as total};
